# **Zachary Lorenzen**

zllorenz@gmail.com (712) 579-5884

217 Peterson Street

Alta IA, 51002

## **Technical Skills:**

Languages: Java, C#, C, C++, Scheme, Prolog, Python, LaTeX, SQL, BASH, Groovy Programs: Microsoft Office, Eclipse, Unity, Blender, SPSS, VIM, Visual Studio, SVN,

OS: Windows, Ubuntu Linux

# **Relevant Projects:**

Software Engineering - HAM

HAM stands for Home Automated Management, and is a project than I and two others students worked on. We simulated a company that provided remote home management to clients, which allowed them to turn lights on and off, and other basic functions. Additional information can be found at our blog: hambvu.blogspot.com

## Computer Science Capstone Project (Undergraduate) – Dias (Unity)

I and one other person formed a small development team that worked on a fully 3D, team-based, competitive multiplayer, arena platformer. Additional information can be found at our blog: *diasdev.blogspot.com* 

#### Data Compression Research

During the summer of 2013 I spent time working on developing and testing a new lossless data compression algorithm with one of my professors at Buena Vista University. Dr. Stone is a professor of physics and computer science, and we tested the new method against static and adaptive Huffman algorithms, the Shannon-Fano algorithm, and others.

## Regression Analysis – Competitive Gaming and Speed

In this study I collected data from over two thousand Starcraft players on how fast they play, their age, and other factors that relate to their gameplay. I used this data to find a correlation between player's speed and their age, in-game army choice, and in-game league.

## **Work History:**

Academic Assistant at Buena Vista University

September 2011 to May 2014

I tutored and held study sessions for math classes including algebra, calculus 1-4, and differential equations. I also occasionally proctored these classes and helped the professor prepare for lectures.

Farm Hand at Lorenzen Farms

2006 to September 2010, May 2016 to October 2018

I helped my father with work on his farm. We raised cattle, hogs and chickens as well as growing crops.

## **Education:**

Graduated: Buena Vista University, Storm Lake IA - GPA: 3.8

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science/Mathematics and Corporate Mathematics